Shijo Chacko

Senior Application Developer

Passionate software Engineer with 14+ years of experience in web applications and back-end systems. Skilled at writing clear, concise code that clear to maintain and trouble shoot. Experienced in working with both small and large teams across multiple projects and companies. Able to work independently of remote locations or in office environment as needed by the company.



Contact

Work History

Address

Oslo, 1356 Norway

Phone

+4793938065

E-mail

shijomeempillil@gmail.com

LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/in/s hijochacko

Website

https://shijochacko.github.io



- Java & Java 17
- Spring
- SpringBoot MicroServices
- Apache Kafka
- Terraform & Docker
- Cosmos & Mongo DB
- JPA & Hibernate
- Git & SVN
- Gradle & Maven
- PostgreSQL & Oracle
- Java Script & Angular
- Junit5
- AWS & Azure Cloud
- Datadog & Splunk
- ETL

Personal Information

Nationality: Indian

Languages: English, Hindi, Malayalam, Norwegian

(Beginner)

Marital Status: Married

Gender: Male

2020-01 -Current

Senior Back-End Developer

Tata Consultancy Services, OSLO

- Lead in Architecture, Design and Development
- Developed 20+ Spring Boot Micro Service applications.
- Developed and maintained microservices architectures using Docker, Kubernetes and Terraform
- Actively involved in Performance tuning of queries in PostgreSQL
- Developed tool and conducted performance testing of Micro Service.
- Designed and executed security measures such as firewalls and encryption.
- Took concepts and produced design mockups and prototypes to strengthen designs, enhance user experiences and improve site interactions.
- Maintained strict budgetary and scheduling guidelines to satisfy customers with high-quality, targeted designs.

2014-07 -2019-10

2012-06 -

2014-06

Senior Full Stack Developer

Tata Consultancy Service, KOCHI

- Developed high performance reporting tool with multiple dashboards.
- Participated in requirements gathering to solidify prerequisites and determine best technical solution to meet business needs.
- Increase customer satisfaction by to 90% by improving report performance.
- Completed full redesigns of existing websites to improve navigation, enhance visuals and strengthen search engine rankings.
- Conceived and built optimized landing pages in HTML and CSS for integration and cross-browser compatibility.

Se

Senior Software Consultant

Computer Sciences Corporation, CHENNAI

- Developed health care fraud detection and analytical tool.
- Designed and developed new tool using JavaScript tool kit in order to provide user inputs.
- Implemented Single Sign-on using spring security.
- Re-Designed Application to connect with multiple



Library design
Agile Workflow
Programming
Performance Tuning
Pair Programming
Mentoring and Training

data bases and handled 40+ client applications request simultaneously.

- Prepared extensive workflow describing input, output and logical operations and converted each into instructions coded in computer language to develop response to web Input.
- Delivered scalable system architecture to support high-availability Internet site with various internal applications.

2010-11 -2012-04

Senior Consultant

IBS SOFTWARE SERVICES, KOCHI

- Development of Internet Booking Engine for budget Airline.
- Managed to handle more than 50k requests per second during peak seasons.
- Proficient in common airline booking software and database management.
- Comprehensive experience with handling multiple booking issues
- Customized application for multiple low budget Airlines.
- Identified new revenue ideas and opportunities within existing markets.
- Increased company revenue through restructuring processes and advising executives on important decisions.

2007-07 -2009-12

Software Engineer

Focuz Innovations, KOCHI

- Reviewed project specifications and designed technology solutions that met or exceeded performance expectations.
- Worked with software development and testing team members to design and develop robust solutions to meet client requirements for functionality, scalability, and performance.
- Delivered unit-tested systems within customerprescribed timeframes.



Education

2003-03 -2006-05

Master of Science: Computer Science

IGNOU - India



Certifications

2009-10

Java

2017-05

Apache Cassandra